every hope you've enjoyed where you've
seen so far the synchronized events and
the three meters for men and for women
we're going to the high board now 10
metre platform competition and we are at
the preliminary stage where we will
whittle down 26 to 18 for the semi-final
and then on to 12 for the final so quite
a quick turnaround for the competitors
here they will compete tonight UK time
in the prelims and then the semi finals
take place early tomorrow morning and
then they'll be back in the evening for
the final not maybe quite as many
competitors as we imagined there would
be but still quite a few so we're gonna
lose 8 tonight
most of the main diving countries are
represented and a few who don't have a
great depth in diving as well as you can
see a big crowd here to welcome the 10
meter competitors they men's by the way
in case you're wondering is on Friday UK
and on Saturday evening will be the
final but this is the preliminary of the
women's 10 metre platform man knows all
about 10 meter having won the synchro
silver medal in 2004 with Pete
Waterfield here's Leon Taylor what a
great shot of the the 10 meter board
those we were hovering above it and then
we can see it now from the more of a
deck level you can see the big drop down
cam just to the right of the 10 meter
we're going to be up close and personal
with the divers following them all the
way down and into the into the water and
there is the list of the divers will see
the list of the dives that they're going
to do a little later on we will have
couple of 16 year olds in here and a 15
year old as well so it is sometimes
considered a young person sport and also
a 14 year old yeah 14 15 and two 16 year
old so barely out of nappies and they'll
be competing on the women's 10 metre
platform here just looking at the stats
on a couple of the divers
about six or seven stone went through
there quite small but I thought I can't
even remember when I was six don't do it
quite nice for those of you watching
around the world will convert the enter
pounds and kilograms for you later on we
did we do it the whole service in if you
want a valet afterwards well sort that
out for you okay so what are we
expecting well it is it is it's a bit of
a marathon actually because the
preliminary scores do not carry through
to the semi-finals and of course the
semi-final scores do not carry through
to the final so you know you could win
the prelim and then it actually makes no
difference it's about driving steady
getting through and shuffling of the
pack so to speak so eighteen divers
going through so only gonna lose eight
which is isn't that many but it will be
highly contested and the girls have to
get up early tomorrow morning so there
won't be to bed until late tonight
finishing here in several hours time up
to three hours this competition is
scheduled to run for late finish back to
the Olympic Village some food try and
sleep full of adrenaline is never easy
and then up early in the morning to come
in and practice those dives once again
the all-important judges seven judges in
the individual competitions I just run
through how the judging works the judges
mark the dive on execution out of a
maximum of ten so if they think it's
okay there maybe give it a five five and
a half if they think it's good maybe a
seven or seven point five they think
it's really really good they might even
go eight and a half and nine those
scores are then collated the two highest
and two lowest judges scores are
discounted they will be shown on the
screen with lines through them to leave
three scores that can't these three war
scores are totaled together and then
multiplied by the degree of difficulty
for that particular dive the degree of
difficulty per dive is calculated on how
complex the dive is that gives a total
score for that dive each of the five
dives count Lisi cumulative score that
counts towards the placings at the end
of round five I hope that makes sense
which we'll revisit
during this long competition we shall
indeed and we still get us about those
marks who lines through hopefully now
we've nailed that so to speak in terms
of what you need to know about scoring
if it's gonna line through it doesn't
if it hasn't $1 that's pretty comes down
to basically and then you multiply that
by the degree of difficulty we're not
gonna be up in the 3.8 stakes here like
we will be in the men's three point
three I think is probably the the top
isn't it yeah I have a quick scan of all
the dive the divers of course submit all
their dives before and they have to go
in different directions we can talk you
through as the competition unfolds five
well there's actually six groups have
dives and the girls have to do five
dives each from a different group see
Brittney viola they're just going
through her visualization she's
visualizing the die because he have
eyelids fluttering there don't worry she
hasn't fallen asleep
she's just preparing herself mentally to
go with a physical preparation because
this needs to be what needs to be right
needs to count and she wants to make it
through she knows she needs five solid
dives twenty-five-year about twenty
five-year-old from America plenty of
experience behind her always to have to
go first she is just enacting the dive
on the top of the board before she gets
involved getting some water out of her
ears there hence the head banging or
head shaking and the towel being thrown
down the Shamy just to keep the drivers
dry so they can hold onto the shape
first I vent for the USA two American
competitors in this competition Brittany
viola is first it's a forward
three-and-a-half summer sorts with Pike
3.0 the degree of difficulty remember
the three marks multiplied by the degree
of difficulty for the total score
well to use and ours from the spectators
and it's very impressive this sport
plenty of support here for the u.s.
diving team they've already got a bag
full of medals from Brittany viola we'll
be looking to for safe passage through
these polymer ease the Pike shaped
folding at the hips beautiful shape
great aerial work it's a good tie for
the American to open up with she sets
sets her marker down pretty good market
it is 270 point 5 0 the mark on the
right hand side of your screen and the
one on the left hand side means that she
is number one in the rankings officer
she would be because she is the first
competitor now from France
Audrey LeBeau getting first lightly less
tariffs dive 2.8 to open up with inwards
two-and-a-half somersaults in the pike
position well over rotating the dive
tips over girls haven't got a lot of
time to wear squeeze all these rotations
in it's sometimes very easy to misjudge
the entry into the water and that's what
we're seeing there from audrey 27 years
old now so she's one of the more
experienced athletes in the field they
see over rotating throwing up too much
splash still landing as I was talking
which means the judges will penalize
that of course we will be down to 18 at
the end of this competition from the
original 26 so she has to make sure
she's in that field it's not the most
auspicious of starts for audrey 6.5
across the main part of our scoring 53.2
zero total mark now Meaghan been Fito
forth in Shanghai at the World
Championships fourth in Rome at the
World Championship what an incentive to
go one better here in London of the
Olympics
very steady very precise great entry
into the water a rip entry Canadians
having some good results here of course
it's young lady along with her partner
got a bronze medal in a very exciting 10
metre platform synchro here she is
individually today and that's a steady
star eight incoming and top of the
leaderboard at this early stage only
three divers in of course yeah it was
3.0 degree of difficulty so can't make a
direct comparison with viola and she
goes further goes higher and goes better
seventy-three point five zero for the
Canadian the first of two Canadians we
will see here comes the Olympic champion
world champion Chen Ruolin 3.0 for three
and a half again the opening dive you
know I should expect on the money from
this last I can't believe that she's
only 19 years old and she's already
Olympic champion at the age of 15 truly
extraordinary that's what we come to
expect from the Chinese of course not
having the wrong way in the pool last
night I'm sure the rest of the world is
infused and you know upbeat about taking
on these two girls today we're shown
reeling will certainly take some beating
and forward three and a half lots of
tape holding it together training so
hard eight point five s to count into
the lead and of course they do hit the
water at 34 35 miles an hour in that
kind of vicinity you already a pro cop
chuck of ukraine for three and a half
again this is a very popular opening
dive for the competitors with pike well
she does okay maybe just tuning as she
went into the water so I could see both
ankles and she went in let's have a look
at the replay to see if what I was
seeing actually happened or whether I'm
making up let's have a look so she's
squeezing into a pike shape needs to be
a little bit tighter there and she goes
in yeah it didn't look quite where it
needed to be on the fin
when we get sevens with an okay start 66
clickety-click Prakash up now the big
roar greets the arrival Oh Stacy Powell
the first of two Britons involving this
composition she's going for a high
tariff driver one of the higher tariffs
dives start off with and there's
anybody's watched our coverage over the
years we'll know I get the jitters with
the arm stance and I still believe
outdoors it should be worth more than
3.2 it is worth 3.2 indoors I keep
banging that drum the I shake my head
every time you say it honest and I'm sat
back at double somersault one and a half
twist there's no wind blowing through
here fortunately so we're no outside
elements to affect Stacy Powell's
everything dive well what a confidence
start coming in her opening dive in the
Olympic Games as if she wouldn't be
nervous enough already decides to show
how confident she is by starting with
this arm stand steady balance bends her
knees flicks off one and a half twist
double somersault of course hands to
hands it's a very neat and tidy dive
just you know leaving a little bit of a
dishes she went into the water which
means she'll probably only get sevens
from the judges but just showing her
confidence yeah she was hearing there a
little bit in the shape maybe going into
the twist a little bit early showing on
the replay there well don't stay skid
start 67 points to zero and we can
definitely promise you loads of chick
flicks
tonight on - Naomi back heat of Italy
going hungry representing Italy yeah you
can see lots of the girls opening up
with this the forward three and a half
as I mentioned at the beginning of the
competition each dive has to be in a
different group this is the forward
group this is the most popular no girls
here will do the forward four and a half
that we see from the men the forward
three and a half pipes and that is a
very very tidy dive from the Italian
no one's giving it away anything yet or
divers landing pretty consistently see
what the judges think of that dive 3.0
degree of difficulty 72 what sir in
third place now just on the lower end of
the tariff start off with not going for
broke straight off yes Kristen Stewart
of Germany in with two and a half summer
sports with pike 2.8 as your seat she
has really ground to make up on the
slightly higher tariff dives and round
one well she's going for a little bit of
an easier degree of difficulty lots of
girls going for the inward three and a
half in the Tuck position which carries
a higher degree of difficulty this the
two and a half in the pike position
spinning forwards it's important you
miss your toes on the diving board which
he does but she moves her hips back a
little bit too much on the start and
spins too slowly finishing very low
that's a very poor dive to start with
from this experienced German diver 29
years old she's been there and done it
several times before but today leaves
herself on the back foot after dive
number one leaves herself at the bottom
of the rung of the pecking order now
eighth place for the German after
opening dive money cladding 3.2 again
like a British teammate Stacy palp
going for my Terry for relatively high
tariff types if the women is 3.2 back
two and a half somersaults one a hard
twists hike this Manik I'm glad to be
here at all relate the story about white
she's very glad to be competing at this
Olympics after we've seen opening dive
oh it's a steady start from both of the
British girls
Monique 31 years old and I bumped into
her family on my way in here to
commentate today and they're so excited
to see him missed out eight years ago
before Athens missed out in Beijing here
she is competing in her first Olympic
Games starting with one more difficult
dives three point two one and a half
twist into the two and a half
somersaults she's had some tough
challenges coming into this with
injuries recently neck and some various
other things but she's here and she'll
be fighting for a place in the
semi-final and she matches her British
teammate Stacy pal they open up with 67
point to 0 both 16 years of age you Dan
oh well there you go
he wasn't wanting to hang around I need
to get the dive done straightaway since
only tiny isn't she ended up short as
she went in the water there which will
cost her she'll only get sevens at best
on this all looks good so far just let's
go a little bit too early and the water
hitting her on the front of her body
there splashed being thrown up not too
much because there wasn't very much of
her to make any splash but this young
lady had been watching you in training
she's formidable she'll be challenging
her teammate ship chain rule in but not
with the dive like that I wonder if she
has got a Chinese upgrade on these
scores here we come 7.5 for who you Dan
60 7.50 is her opening mark now from it
was republic of korea it's kim yang and
we've seen already quite a few times
forward three and a half somersaults
with pike very popular dive first round
this one with Mike oh wow she really
attacked that didn't she probably gave
it a little bit too much and you can
quite clearly say the over rotation into
the into the water she absolutely motors
this landing on the end
divers choosing to use a towel maybe it
gives a bit more grip but it certainly
diver preference but look at that over
she goes for force 4.5 probably that is
quite far over vertical
and she'll have some work to do on the
golf course remain there shouting four
five four and a half and a five for Kim
coming hang and that's not gonna do her
chances of progression much good at all
here's brittany broman sixteen years of
age from australia those tariffs we've
seen so far 2.7 on this reverse two and
a half several sorts with tuck oh it's a
beautiful dive to open up with only 16
years old haven't seen much of this girl
at all the new girl on the block there's
a coach he likes to start to reverse so
you're standing forwards jumping away
from the diving board spinning backwards
beautiful technique just tipping over a
vertical slightly that's going to get
eight and eight point five it's a
beautiful start very confident for a
young 16 year old Ozzy's on the board
whether it be three meter or ten meter
have been quite confident so far and he
point fives across the board for her
gives her a sixty eight point eight five
with that opening round dive second one
of the Italians now Brenda spazzy on e
2.8 they only will be well beyond my
compass and probably yours at home as
well
inward to and our summer sorts with Pike
opening dive
well I think you could see the nerves
there at home couldn't you so she was
twitching the cameraman zoom right in on
it on the on the thumbs and fingers she
little bit close to the diving board you
can see a flattening of feet there this
is the danger on this dive is very easy
to tip your toes on it it doesn't hurt
but it does throw you off look at this
dip oh no she just misses the diving
board that does put her boots on as she
goes by in order to miss it it's a
technical diving turn putting your boots
on I'm sure you're getting into it now
look at that beautiful super slow motion
into the entry there from the fixed
cameras a little bit off the mark for
Brenda fifty four point six zero and
those indulging in the Leon Taylor
drinking game
that's probably your first one of the
evening now Karolina I mean those are
Hernandez of Mexico again it's a for
three and a half somersaults with Pike
and again you can compare and contrast
as dive with plenty of the others in the
first round this is an exciting divers
he's only 15 years old and I'm just
looking down the her list of dives and
she is bringing out the big guns for her
competition here this is of easiest dive
at 3.0 everything else is really really
tricky she's got a lot of tape on there
on her back again we discussed this
every time lots of the divers held
together by sticky tape this young
Mexican just on the down the right-hand
side of her back they're obviously
suffering as many of these divers to I
do because of the strains of the sport
seven point five and sevens will count
towards the total and she gets sixty
four point five zero second of the
Canadians are Rosaleen feel it's gonna
be that's yeah you seen it before and
you'll see it many more times every
diver will do this pretty much see for
three and a half seven sorts with Pike
3.0 degree of difficulty
very steady just like a teammate of
course they were bronze medalists nearly
last week and that's got to make you
feel good coming into your individual
event riding on a high although they've
had a bit of a wait and no more waiting
around now this is it you're in prelims
there's the little over a vertical
strong powerful takeoff squeezing into
the pike there we go
so what'd you get for that she got 63 my
favourite score of the week 7 x 3 degree
of difficulty gives you 63 and now it's
pretty seen Melissa whoop in the synchro
the other day but she wasn't there cuz
and she didn't make it through so here
she is in the individual yeah but she'll
have a point to prove here had to wait
patiently all week watching her
teammates I've been been on right from
the start lands perfectly on the end
long legs looks good when she's spinning
around just a little bit of splashes she
goes in but that's a really solid start
here come eight maybe even 8.5 s-stupid
dive yeah I saw it start for Melissa
woods had to wait a long time I having
been involved in the timid synchro the
other day back in with three-eighths 72
smart on the coach gets from the coach
happy now Maria Carillo of Germany
yeah you're getting used to seeing this
dive now just probably a little bit too
much philosophy and thrown up there and
it knows so much about this German he's
done very well to make the team highly
contested on the platform what's the
teammate fault of earlier looking to
pick up from that she's done a
reasonable job just a little low on the
water throwing at the splash they're
going back towards the diving board
there we go look at the view of the
Aquatic Center that front on shot there
with the eyes iconic diving boards
certainly are many many tons of
concrete's gone into that many hours of
preparation for Maria Carillo who's
there 6.5 s in the opening round dive
his another person who was involved in
the sync really owed a pang of Malaysia
well welcome pundit Leno that's a
beautiful dive and it works very hard
again often has injury troubles let's
see how much tape she's sporting yet
both ankles both wrists but she
certainly gets going there look at that
pike shakes you almost has a chin on her
ankles that's incredible flexibility and
there's a beautiful dive as well should
put a top of the pile or there abouts
after the first round or so far yeah
just didn't try that at home
putting your chin on your ankles you
might do yourself a mischief for the
divers
our opening score is 72 quite a popular
one three three divers on that mark 72
chen leading the way pan Fito in second
kim jin OCH from people's republic of
korea kim yep for three and a half oh
it's a very tidy type good entry into
the water just a little over vertical as
she goes in otherwise a very good effort
strong powerful take off you could these
divers all plenty of tape everywhere
ankles calf's trying to hold themselves
together it's a very solid start
can we be very pleased with that
I wonder if the coaches will never
really know where the coaches another 72
that seems to be the popular score
tonight four girls on that thanks Annie
Rivera of Cuba difference for you this
time lower degree of difficulty 2.8 for
the inward two and a half summer sorts
with pike very very safe distance from
the diving board and I mentioned last
time we watched this dive it is only two
point eight degree of difficulty moves
it away the safe distance so she didn't
have to flatten her feet she goes by
there we go and then just hangs on a
little bit too long in the pike shape
@gs tips over a vertical look at the
splash going back towards the diving
board
fives probably for that effort and some
work to do how generous the judges
feeling 5.5 s who will into account so
three scores discounted four scores
discounted and three will remain in
place now Tracy took yet Malaysia
opted for the dive that pretty much
everybody else in the first round has
the for three and a half
yeah just rolling into the water not
quite straightening out she went in so
the judges will take some marks off for
that even though the entry was clean
minimal splash she didn't quite complete
the dive in time so yeah lots of divers
opting for the forward three and a half
in the pike position it is 3.0 some of
the girls might do it in the Tuck
position but all girls choosing to do
the forward group of course they've got
six groups to choose from the forward is
only one of six so you will see some
variance but it seems to be a popular
opener in the women's competition
yeah 66 this time 7.5 times to seven ran
up to a total I was mentioning about
weights and Heights earlier on you know
as Katie belt 6:30 eleven I should
prefer 48 kilograms 18 pounds
okay I'll compose smile take a
perspiration off the fingers it's
counting yourself anything
well she was having a chat with the
South before she ran off the the end of
the ten meter board there I wonder what
she was saying I was curious we weren't
quite close enough to the speakers to
hear I think Bob my Bob's guests may
have may be accurate of counting
yourself in you know sometimes divers do
a little I used to talk to myself but
only in my head I used to say some yeah
but I'm speaking into the microphone now
so you can all hear my thoughts lucky
you all at home anyway not so lucky for
young miss belt just over a vertical and
she went in you can see how small she is
there next to her if every talk coach
it's quite a contrast isn't it yeah
Casey bell dropping a clangor on her
opening round now power Espinoza Sanchez
our Mexico watched this girl she's
pretty decent bronze medalist in the
world's last year oh yeah four hurt now
already silver medalist in the 10-meter
synchro and as bob was mentioning a
phenomenal athlete known for her spring
and power and dynamic diving and not so
well known for landing over a vertical
on an opening dive however it was a good
dive apart from the fault on the entry
so she's very high and it was a good
good shape in the air so they're not
gonna go to town on her so much it's
making her way back there so on the mark
cs7 she gets away with it there may be a
reputation saving her yeah she will
improve I'm sure she'll be back we'll
hope she'll be back for the semi-final
because she's a very entertaining and
very classy individual when it comes to
this competition now secondly of the arm
stands I'm not looking Yuliya colton
over not quite as complicated as Stacey
pounds the arm stand forward double
somersault one twist with free still
difficult enough oh what an entry what
an absolute beauty of an entry yes
disappeared into the water hardly a
ripple of splash wow that really is
quite something arm stamp balance
flicking off here we go there's a one
twist it's the double somersault
it's tricky there's a lot going on I
think it's more
complicated than the 3.1 but there we go
what an entry maybe squeeze some nines
from the judges hardly a droplet
splashes she goes in even on the slow
motion and that dive takes her into the
lead seventy nine point zero five ahead
are Chen and Ben feet oh who were four
one and two they're now 2 and 3 and the
Russian 24th diver and the competition
goes into the lead
my Nakagawa arm Japan inwards
two and a half with Mike your beautiful
dive on Nakagawa yeah there we are the
friends and family here from all over
the world to support these athletes just
touching their toes on the diving board
though I didn't see that in real speed I
don't think the judges will see it
either because she didn't falter but she
did danke toes on the diving board now
because he didn't affect the dive in the
judges don't get the replays I think she
got out she could hang with it well done
done that's a poker face as well as
though she wasn't gonna give anything
away there seventy one point four zero
four
Nakagawa now the last diver the youngest
diver in the competition when you get
along with it - oh no no guess it's
there what happened there splash giving
it away legging it into the end of the
diving board all looks okay so far and
that's now is when you want to come out
oh just over she goes Louis going diver
the competition from the youngest diver
in the competition Kim from Korea 14
years of age he is
phors give me a total of 36 and the
coach is not gonna be relenting in terms
of passing on his wisdom slap on the
fight and the end of the first round of
the women's 10 meters platform and the
preliminary standings after round 1 I'll
turn over Chen and benefit 0 1 2 3
plenty in 4th place top 18 remember
going through and at the moment both of
the British divers are going through
just well don't have a dime often I'm
sure they won't happen but at the bottom
joint 17th and these are the ones who
have a little bit of work to do even at
this early stage and you think the two
Kim's probably not going to be involved
in the shake-up at the end even at this
stage
very impressive arena this the Aquatic
Center in Olympic Park and beautifully
shaped ten meter board really
artistically everything about this venue
has been artistic let's see whether
Brittany viola can be artistic on her
arm stand back at double somersault one
and a half twist three point two a
degree of difficulty and about 30 feet
up no Marja forever Ferrara with those
feet right over the edge and taking all
the weight
well it's dramatic isn't it balancing on
the end you could see put these mum
there holding her breath as a daughter
lifted herself up with perfect control
into that arm stamp bending the knees
it's called the flick one and a half
twist squares it up nicely on the end
finishes accurately on the water nice a
curve and I've servile looks very very
focused I've not seen it look so focused
working for so far yeah good mark for
her coach will never be happy of course
in this thing she can't improve on it
for next time around crying she's there
seventy-three point six zero for viola
of the USA in there Audrey in the boat
and the fifty three point two to start
with so she's got a bit of ground to
make up already she's not into the
threes yet two point nine degree of
difficulty on this back two and a half
summer sorts with Mike for the French
woman voice a very good entry short of
vertical but she manages to hold
attention hold her body tension and get
a very very good rip entry into the
water it's a relatively easy dive in
comparison to some of the others two
point eight degree two point nine degree
of difficulty I beg your pardon but when
it's done like that'll get a reasonable
score and keep her well upping a game
actually from the first round I've yeah
certainly a big improvement from the
first round
fifty three up to sixty eight now the
degree of difficulty was slightly
improved and the dive itself was very
much improved their round after the
third after the first round let's
rearrange these words in it to make a
sentence Megan Ben feet o of Canada
going with a back three-and-a-half
samasource look at the difficulty right
at the top of the shop here three point
three on this one
rawrr she's landed it very well indeed
it's high-risk so Audrey before her
opting for the backward two-and-a-half
in the pike position 2.9 degree of
difficulty this the backward a three and
a half three point three degree of
difficulty so if you get it right it can
work for you and megan has done just
that she get on this seven half stand
eights I think leave her smiling after a
second round I've I'm sure the marks
without the lines through them the ones
account eight eight and seven point five
multiplied by the degree of difficulty
that's how we arrive at seventy-seven
point five five
now the olympic and world champion chen
rule in second after round one in with
three and a half Witek when a three
point two in terms of degree of
difficulty
or throwing up more splashing I was
expecting the entry seemed to be well
all in order if you like so she
disappeared but then this big volcano of
splash came up afterwards take off is
very good seems to be all good from here
I bite into the water as a vertical
entry but look at that bubbles up like a
geyser Keita I don't know what they call
those things that bubble up water what
are they called Bob
Ziggy's around here you believe you
didn't response East End remember yep
that's chain rule in yeah geez are we
fine yeah it worked now onto a olia
Prokop chuck of Ukraine and I'm peeing
the stakes for most of them now in with
three and a half somersaults 3.2 with
tuck 14th after round 1 she stays there
she'll be fine for the semi war very
good indeed finishing a little bit low
on the water teammates like it hush up
and featured yesterday's final cheering
on his teammate here and there we go
safe distance from the diving board yes
I know it's not far away but it's saved
a little bit low on the water but she's
very sneaky on that finish that could
get 80 points and if it does then she'll
be way up there after the second round
anything in the 70s is good Oh 80 and I
won't count hi mark but 80 is high mark
and that will move far up the standings
quite some way decent opening for Stacy
Powell with the armstand
spell I want out of the way now she can
concentrate on another high tariff dive
three point three so I tariff program
this a lot of risk attached to it but if
it works out and you go shooting into
the semi-final that's obviously the plan
for Stacey power back three and a half
somersaults with tuck three point three
for the first of the Britons diving in
round two
or that could prove to be critical Stacy
with some work to do this is the only
dive in a program that could potentially
have leather dye and it's a highest
degree of difficulty it's the one that
could have gone wrong and unfortunately
for Stacy is the one that does go wrong
she lets go of a shape way too early
they're loose in the lower back bending
the knees she's gonna get thumped by the
judges on that the marks will be very
low here's the drop down cam just
showing where all goes wrong there we
are that isn't gonna be very nice either
scoreboard Stacy had to walk away about
a year twenty nine point seven zero any
of those threes count agony for her I
think good thing is it's not a big field
so there is time to repair the damage
and the people of course good for Terron
their dives come back here Italy back
two and a half somersaults with pike two
point nine threes yet yet playing it
safe we saw Stacy Powell former team GP
DEP ending her back three and a half
which is an option in this backward
movement group very very short backed in
here playing safe and it proves a better
gamble they'll get mid-60s very tidy
only two point nine degree of difficulty
but it performed very well indeed that
super-slow-motion
difficult so he zoomed in that foul on
the diver we get an idea of what's going
on solid from back heat sixty five point
two five will do her power of good in
terms of getting that top at eighteen
place now to a Christian step of Germany
was in the threes three point two on his
back
two-and-a-half somersaults one half
twists performed in the pike position
she needs a few points she's back in
twenty second after a fairly poor first
round dive
well right on cue she required some more
points and this is the dive to do it on
her most difficult in the program three
point two degree of difficulty near poor
opening inwards
actually this heavily strapped up there
but didn't seem to affect her entry into
the water one and a half twist two and a
half somersaults and then yeah sneaks it
in there with a rip entry that will help
her right
seven point five a smile and all nod at
the coach and seventy-two for stir money
planning its mouth equal after round one
she has gone from a high tariffs dive to
start up with to a much more low tariffs
dive for round two and taking all the
time that she can for preparation is
there a time limit you know under the
referees discretion that's right but the
referees only just blown the whistle now
so he has money we'll have as much time
as she needs within reason if the
referee think she's taking too long they
can restart no in words
two and a half somersaults with Mike two
point eight
oh it's very good I was holding my
breath then the reason being is that
this particular move of dive is the dive
that money dramatically last year hits
her head on the diving board it was a
different dive to this one it is the
inward three and a half she hit her head
on the diving board and needed to be
rescued from the bottom of the pool
unconscious in Russia by a teammate
Nikolas and Robertson Baker fortunately
she's made this amazing comeback now
this dive that she's been performing
instead in with two-and-a-half in the
pipe position you feet could come a
little bit close and she has been
hitting her feet in training so it's
been a really tough time you can see the
relief on her face there sevens across
the board oh look I've got away with
that one sevens and fifty-eight cuz the
low degree of difficulty bit but up into
the top six for now
who you Dan the sixteen year old from
China in with three and a half we tuck
3.2 for her second dive oh it's good
entry but it is over so I say good entry
as in clean with not very much splash
look at Rumi shower they're saying look
she went flying over and yes she did we
should come up here and provide the
commentary here we are in with
three-and-a-half in the Tuck position
nothing wrong with that tuck position
there she goes woo arching in the lower
back over she goes that'll get sevens I
think well they should get sevens
because yeah it's a shame really she did
all the hard work on sevens eight and
seven point five ins has been great
pleasure working with you now on to Kim
on yang the People's Republic of Korea
in with three and a half we're TUC 3.2
again and a little bit of ground to make
up after that - that's an auspicious
start shall we say
well that's a better second round I've
should having a good think about it
drivers balancing on their tiptoes
interns not to be so sensible to hang
around for too long your legs can get
tired just on your tiptoes is it work
anyway
Kym making a better effort on this
second round divert in with three and a
half your hair comes pretty close
doesn't it he never very far away that's
a little bit too close we're just
talking about money cladding hitting a
head you can see how it happens there we
go
hands up how many of you at home have
recoiled on a couple of those dives
tonight because that is immensely close
and that concrete is unforgiving as my
glaring found out in Russia now on to
Brittany roben of Australia in were
three and a half for her as well tuck
position three point two well that's
such a shame the area work is very good
she was completing the dive with ease in
fact and then she just maybe panicked a
little bit and comes out at the dive a
little bit earlier that's the safe
distance from the diving board and then
just stretches forward a little bit too
much ending short of vertical there so
six and a half's probably which is a
shame because if she waited in a touch
tape a little bit longer she'd have been
on for eight maybe twenty three marks to
be calibrated calculated and put on the
scoreboard 6.5 raw brittany broman and
sixty two point four zero the total mark
moving up from a position of ten that
around one brenda spazzy ani of Italy
for three and a half summer sorts with
Pike 3.0
just finishing short she goes in there
it's a difficult dive 3.0 you need to
really attack the takeoff Brenda does
attack you she doesn't quite get in a
pike shape you see you can see there's
some daylight in between her thighs and
chess set needs to squeeze in a little
bit tighter in order to make the dive
with ease and give her a chance to get
that entry right and the marks please
judges can we have now a six point zero
right across the board times three
working out basic maths for you this
time 54
here's her total mark right arm stand
time oh goody
hey back triple somersault with tuck
three point three the degree of
difficulty again I think we might find
that those are Fernandez might just take
a little while over this step right
hands positions right
and wait until she's in solid position
wavering a bit ready to go she does a
good job of course the she's under the
judges rather the judges are actually
judging her right from the you know soon
as the referee's whistle goes so soon as
she starts to lift up you know she's
wobbling around the judges will see that
and they could take off some some marks
for not showing control but she seemed
pretty controlled to me and in the dive
a little bit short but it's a big degree
of difficulty is a difficult dive
holding on to a top of a kneecap so she
that's very well to stay in a tux shape
thrown up too much splash 4/8 but sevens
maybe it is sevens and a 6.5 just as
being quite tight on their scoring
tonight for the most part sixty seven
point six five four Mendoza and then
this it's not gonna hide away now
Roslin fiddy up back three and a half
somersaults with tuck three point three
saving her arm Santa a little bit later
just inside that cut off of the top 18
in 17th oh yeah indeed it was a big dive
and we've seen a couple of the girls
faltering on this one Stacy Powell is an
example this time Rosaline actually
hanging on to a touch shape long enough
she's running out of room holding on to
the tops of her knees there she pops her
feet right upper chest tips over tries
to save it by bending your knees and
then causes a bit of a boom water-wise
as she goes in that's not going to get
too much over fifty points at that level
or interesting Roslyn filly on shaky in
the room that boom five point five and a
four point five for the Canadian not
quite what she wanted at this stage
on - Melissa Wu of Australia
it's armstand time everybody back double
somersault one and a half twists free
position explain that very quickly on
free position yeah when the dive isn't
diver isn't rotating for more than one
somersault of a twist it means a free
position so you don't actually hold a
position for more than a half a
somersault
so you see Melissa stay relatively
straight throughout this and then just
re Pike on the finish to enter the water
three point two degree of difficulty no
she does a really superb job on that
finish yep there's a lot going on you're
flicking off your hands one and a half
twist double somersault it's a lot to
get in in such a short amount of time
there's a one and a half twist
Reed pikes there we are the free
position and very tidy and that's gonna
get eight and that's gonna move her up
the field see what the total mark is
after a 72 to start she finds that with
a seventy six point eight zero quite
solid from Wu and she is up to third
place right now - Maria Cayo Germany
three point two arm stand back a double
somersault one half twist again in the
free position I've seen that an awful
lot another dive competition so I
thought we just under my it's not tuck
or pike say it slowly let me say puck
and Tyco
it's a good dive I'm running out of room
a little bit she goes into there's a
little bit scruffy here we are bending
the arms trying to flick up generate
height from the arms as you can see here
it's good you know I'm probably being a
little unfair she did have time to
finish it off properly it'll get sevens
not all that's better than her first
round effort and she'll be pleased with
it's a great shot from above here look
at that even in slow motion the divers
hit the water fast don't they
it looks more than 30 feet doesn't it
when they leap off the board like that
suppose win it they're going up this is
more than 33 feet isn't it yes now and
pang of Malaysia for the big stakes yet
2.9 back two and a half with pike you're
beautiful
cruising opting for the back two and
half pipes she could easily make back
three and a half but she's opting for
the easier one here we go up into the
pike shape that beautiful Pike shape
spotting the water pointing a toes right
time making the dive looks so beautiful
and it works out for her my opinion
that's worth a nine and there's a
beautiful dive now let's see whether
neons thoughts are transmitted to the
judges on the far side have just
inputted their scores just coming up on
the scoreboard our rights
and coming up on your score poor now on
your screen seventy five point four zero
nines what she is given him Janaki
Oh career he was Republic of Korea
inward three and a half summer sorts
with tucky 3.24 fast around 100 well she
won't be forth after vine to falling
away from the diving board way too far
there which makes it difficult it's
almost like a trap door open does she
take took off from the diving board and
there she goes disappearing through the
trapdoor running out of room and then
doesn't quite says two bikes at the
cherry as she tries to come out of the
dive straightening from the hips and
then from the knees yeah the judges will
go to town on that one and won't give
her very good marks at all
which in a rather strange fashion there
the knees were bent this year she went
in slightly a rakish angle judges a
disagreement two up to four point five
on the screen there were only the top
and bottom marks will count work out
through middle ones that will Rivera off
Cuba well such a shame she's got great
aerial work she gets these dives moving
and she doesn't seem to have very much
an idea where she is now that could be a
big problem when you're diving you need
to know pretty much exactly where you
are
proprioception and kinesthetic feedback
ie where you are in relation to the
water in this case anyway she's in and
over lots of splash coming up and that
puts head right at the bottom of the
pack you have just Union you're not
listen to the Open University worse than
they come from
they're real words you could look about
if you want in your dictionary again
Rivera
54 remarks takes her to only 19th of the
moment it's not gonna do it for her for
qualification Tracy took yet of Malaysia
in with three and a half somersaults
with tuck 3.20 over she goes we're gonna
see this a little bit the girls out
there today they've got such complex
dives to do and when you're doing such
complex dives they can easily go wrong
and Tracy here just unfortunately
letting that dive go on the end there
over you can see the splash going back
almost said surfboards which I think you
might need to explain the drinkie gape
of there's some confusion I think
there's some of my second Anna fine I
think there's some of my my diet my
commentary finds out they have designed
a drinking game with some of my more
frequent sayings and I think get your
surfboards I is one of them so I think
that's a drink for those of you playing
at home have you worried too tiddly by
the end of this competition now on to
the American Katie Bell let's see what
she does in terms of preparation this
time she's talking to herself smiling to
herself a right old chatter she's saying
yeah
yes yes yeah five six seven eight it's
Sesame Street oh it's a difficult dive
as well reverse two and a half not in
the tuck position but in the pike
position so it carries a higher degree
of difficulty than the Tuck position so
it's two point nine I think you should
be worth more than this two point nine
because that's really tricky you're
jumping away spinning backwards
it makes me well shift in my chair every
time I watch a diver perform this dive
Katie just leaving it short they're
running out of space to squeeze the dive
in you can see the splash moving away
from the diving board see the diver here
moving the arms to the side with all
that air coming down trying to you know
cause that suction for the river entry
not quite working for Bell no she hasn't
got it going yet five point five is six
but that doesn't count
that's not the market she really wanted
I from the first round all the second
round she finds herself cast adrift in
21st not seeing anything about Espinoza
Sanchez now after putting the mouth on
her in the first round so to speak back
three and a half seven sorts with tuck I
think you'll continuing to do that by
just suggesting it Bob she is all over
the shop Wow I was watching training she
looked on silver medal earlier this well
last week now in the synchronized 10
meter and for a world medalist this
isn't very good at all
the aerial works good and that is way
over loads of splash she's only gonna
get fours that best Wow three dives to
go I don't know that's too much to burn
OSHA I think she can come back but Wow
yeah she should be out if she's got some
big dive still to come but 20th place
not were expected the bronze medalists
from Shanghai to beat at this stage of
the competition that was only 12 months
ago or so she won that bronze medal in
the world championships Junior gotten
over Russia in the back three and a half
she needed a ten and a half metre
platform to get that dive in there this
is the risk you run well but I have
these conversation why do some people go
for the lower degree of difficulty well
this is why because the higher degree of
difficulty carries so much risk there we
go just hitting the water bond the back
it feels like a bat around the back of
the head as you go in there oh your
shoulders are sore it's like a car crash
or being pulled to the side well she's
made a tough stuff doesn't seem to
flinch but that will hurt tomorrow
morning for sure I think the marks will
hurt more than the actual entry into the
water
not sure only forty seven point eight
five four I'll turn over like a cow up
of Japan for a slight variance in what
we've seen so let's give lot in the
first round other divers forward three
and a half summer sorts with pike noir
beautiful rep entry into the water from
Nakagawa they like it the fans
supporters and family here make shouting
and screaming that's a very good dive
yeah look at that pike shape her Chin's
almost on a rang course it's incredible
the flexibility in some of these girls
spines and bodies makes a dive very easy
you can get into a tight pipe shape and
Nakagawa it's certainly doing that with
an entry to boot backs up a 70 1.40 with
a 72 and she goes on like that she'll be
comfortably into the top 18 for the
semi-final Kim off career however he's
not in that kind of realm at the moment
twenty-sixth with that in with three and
a half again 3.2
well the youngest competitor certainly
showing him in experience here today was
watching training and actually you know
she's always going to struggle it's a
big ask at such a tender age to be
coming into an Olympic Games and
performing these dives and that's a
particularly difficult 13.2 she's got
even more difficult one next round so
I'll be holding my breath when she does
that one hoping that she is okay and
yeah that isn't gonna be good
26 for Kim after the second round I've
seen a lot of 4.5 today not gonna help
the progression of those who give her a
top 18 place these are the divers who
are very safe and with a bit of room for
error I benefited a good start Chen has
my list of whoo my down to nine or in
reasonably comfortable territory it's a
little bit tighter up to 18 or in
including Monica cladding of Great
Britain Rosalie and Finlay on in the
last position at the moment and these
are the ones on the next page and we're
gonna have little work to do down to
Stacey Powell in 25th and Kim of career
in 26 kg belt Stacey Powell and Kim
master drift a little bit not at three
figures yet
stacy pal I was plating her dive in
round three
and here is round three of the women's
10 metre platform preliminary top 18 go
through to the semi-final top 12 then to
the final at the moment
Brittany viola is comfortable in 6th
place after her first two rounds she's
gonna here for an inward three and a
half samasource with tuck in round 3 Sun
off the divers in this competition
well shame really all she needed to do
was straighten out a little bit more she
went into the water
great Brittany says the banner not quite
great enough on that dive every work is
good squeezing into that touch sit quite
near the diving board and then does it
quite straight now and you can see the
backside just poking out a little bit
there if she just straightened out more
she went in she'd get more than sixes
6.5 you know she was running a little
bit higher but again for Louise it's
just about making it through mmm
Brittany oh baby baby 6 is fifty-seven
point six zero for Brittany viola Audrey
LeBeau France occupying 16th place which
will be good enough if she retains out
for the next three rounds
first of all you've been proving to be a
little bit problematic so far in the
competition and she has hers right now
arm stand back double somersault one and
a half twists three point to the degree
of difficulty well it's a good tie from
Audrey just over rotating as she goes in
and some of you may have seen as Audrey
was lifting up into the handstand there
was a technical official on the back of
the 10 meter board there is a reason for
this because if the diver doesn't get up
into the handstand successfully first
time and they come down that's a
technical fault it actually becomes a
restart so the technical official at the
top of the 10 meter is there to make
sure that the athlete does not restart
it's important part it's part of the
FINA rules I know some of you have been
questioning that whether it's off
putting the technical official stands to
the side out of the way hope that
explains that focal 160 2.40 as we
explain the marks for you again all the
marks without lines through them count
multiplied by the degree of difficulty
again bent feet it was had a very good
start for the mouth of her eye there
kiss to have the commentators curse
tonight in word three and half
somersaults difficulty 3.2 for the first
of the Canadians
I think you should keep quiet Bob I just
did the commentary on my own otherwise
we could see all sorts happening so make
in first two times as we mentioned very
good indeed
third round dive and I'm surprised
because this one it's actually normally
pretty solid for it she was another one
who needed an 11 meter platform that's a
real shame lost it all on the take-off
doesn't get enough spring struggles on
the rotation and then yeah the entry is
impacted negatively it's all over when
it started actually I didn't Rosen that
kind of influence but seemingly I do
fives a three point two and that has
taken a tumbling down the table but I
think she's probably done enough for the
first two rounds ourself with a bit of a
buffer and of a comfort zone margin for
round five when we get to it
general in the champion world champion
second place after round two becomes the
arm stand from her
yeah no mistakes from Shen Ruolin so
experienced and this is very very
technically proficient straight up and
down right on the money big scores
coming her way
one and a half twist straight down into
the water repent tree 98.5 at worst 3.2
equals the lead have that 10 meter board
measured to no unsafe thinking this it
might be nine and a half or ten eleven
to be working for everybody tonight it's
worked for her eighty one point six zero
and that takes her into quite a
commanding lead
of course the marks from the prelims are
not carried forward to the semi-final
just in case of earning yourself a place
you only Oprah cop shook back two and a
half well she almost had it there it all
looked good I think she just needed to
look back a little bit with her chin
sorry with it yeah lift her chin a
little bit look back at the water to
glide that dive in she just doesn't look
back far enough for me so instead of
being completely upright she's a little
bit out of shape on the end on the end
of the dive making much sense there but
I think I will on this area I've just
needed to look back a little bit more to
glide into the water with a slight back
arch for eight so 17 bit bit of a mixed
bag from the judges sixty five point two
five for the book took no Stacie Pannell
needs all the support and all the help
she can get from the home crowd because
that second round dive quite a drop dive
the attempted marks it wasn't quite what
she wanted so she hasn't got to the
three figure mark yet ninety six point
nine zero after round two
can she repair some of that damage with
a for three and a half somersaults with
pike
yeah she can repair the damage she's
gonna have to get a comeback floors I
dig them in and pull herself back into
contention
the cried certainly like it they're
looking for that repent tree and there
certainly was one on the end of that
dive little bit back from the end and
she is a little bit piked as she entered
the water so I don't think she's gonna
get ate but she certainly deserves 7.5
there's a real shame if she was
completely straight on the entry into
the water and then I think she should be
getting nines good dive from Stacey to
pull her back into it oh good
they've gone with her eight well one
seven one seven point five but they
don't count so eight two came yes Emily
to the total mark that will move her up
a spot or two she needs to be about
quite a few though she has to get eight
places to make that so many fine but
that it's not beyond redemption
onto the diaper with a Hungarian name
born in Hungary but representing Italy
there's no me back key never been beyond
the preliminaries and any major event so
far this be her turn back 2 & a half
somersaults 1 the half twists in the
pike position was the biggest I was
watching him earlier
maybe suffering a little bit of injury a
coach was given a bit of a massage in
between the shoulder blades the divers
getting ripped here there and everywhere
as they enter the water if your head
goes one way and you arm goes the other
it does feel like your shoulders being
dislocated there we are putting
themselves through all sorts of
punishment to bring you the
entertainment of the evening and that
was good from Italian yeah it's a pretty
solid mark Ashley coming up on your
screen sixty seven point two zero
certainly the in the context of this
competition if you again 67's we're so
you'd be pretty happy because it would
mean that you make it through to the
last eighteen she is on her way Kristen
Stewart of Germany in the preparation
for that 3.2 degree of difficulty dive
arm stand back double somersault one a
half twist you hear the crowd didn't
take a breath as I watch here get in the
upright position than those heavily
bandaged wrists well she just seemed to
fall off the diving board there didn't
even push with her hands just seemed to
use the momentum falling is a very
brightly coloured costume isn't it thank
you my eyes go a little bit a little bit
funny anyway the dive is good did she
show control in the balance maybe some
of the judges will you know take some
marks off for that maybe just half a
point apart from not very much height
from the hands is straight up and down
she does a good job
72 for Kristen Stewart just examining
the board only what's good have known a
bit better I think she can think about
improving on that and semi final she may
be on her way monie cladding it's in
14th place after round 2 it's time for
her arm stand it's over with money just
taking it with extra preparation time
said I've you've seen several times arm
stand back double somersault one half
twists right
intricate laborious preparation for
Maalik
well you could hear an absolute pin drop
couldn't you Monique a next gymnast from
South Africa coming in to her arm stand
as if she's on the balance beam she
comes in from the side always scares me
doing that I would never have got into
my arm standing that way she held holds
the arms done beautifully very steady
great home support just a little bit of
over votation I think she'll get away
with Sarah's look at that coming inside
on as if she's on the balance beam but
she's not she's perched on the enter the
10 meter this is such a strong jump just
giving it a little bit too much revving
the engine a little bit too hard over
rotating graduation from a Melissa whoo
they're from Australia good friends yeah
it's a fairly solid score though and in
the context of this competition may well
be good enough mid-range score and
things have been thus far mid-range
score just about gets the job done
whoo you Dan well replicate in terms of
the dive that we've just seen from Manik
three-point-two arm stand back double
somersault one and a half twists oh it's
a good entry from you Dan however she is
tipping over a vertical remember seeing
a previous two dice both of them a
little bit off on the entries so we're
see only very young as she's 16 I've
seen the dive so much better than this
I'm sure there's more to come I mean
she's going to get good marks on that
but in training I've seen this worth
nines and tens actually that's 8 mm
maybe
yeah 8 that's what I'd go for and that
judges think
exactly the way you're thinking pretty
much and there was an 8.5 it's like you
broke one in there 8 otherwise and again
as we expect the Chinese are gonna be
they are they're about at the end of
this competition now two slightly more
complicated arm stand back triple
somersault here or Kim of Korea Korea
gonna be over
this over she goes throwing up a lot of
splash the the lifting to the arm
balance into the umpires was absolutely
superb very gymnastic showing very solid
good control and then flicks off gets
into the shape it's all looking good
until there and then whoosh there's a
big tidal wave Shane look at the splash
finesse whoosh it's behind you the mark
is forty six point two zero we'll just
spread on that two point five up to five
five point five one of them two point
five to five point five eighths confuse
the judges that one befuddled if I don't
good words yeah they couldn't work it
out they might do it better on Brittany
bro burns arm stand like me a three and
a half point differential but we're
revisiting old sores and old wounds
aren't we on this one
I'm stand back double somersault one and
a half twists case you're coming in
fresh to the competition we've seen this
a lot this is the attempt by the 16 year
old Australian Brittany browbone
in round three well I'm impressed with
this young lady only 16 years old and
she's holding it together very composed
yep having a smile as well and good on
you that's what it's all about
nice well have some fun this is what you
do day in day out week after week month
after month
hour after hour now it's your time to
shine and that's three out of three for
the Aussie yeah 68-62 and 80
are happy with her and she will be happy
with that she goes up to 211 and the
well on her way three more rounds to go
of course
two more rounds to go after this it's
five in the women's six in the men's and
spazzy alley
still going for the high tariffs still
sticking in the twos 2.9 for the Italian
back two and a half soy sauce
yeah well you enjoy didn't look like she
was conducting an orchestra then just
before she took off well it's the arm
swing that she chose to use and it
seemed to be pretty effective let's have
a look at the take off I we didn't get
to see the arm swing then she's moving
sideways a little bit
none of our movement there that she
probably didn't need a bit of splash
being thrown up Oh big back arch she
takes off by Carter she goes in not the
problem still on
maybe sheets you find a job there she
doesn't qualify in here fifty two point
two zero a baton she'd be well away now
on to Karenina Hernandez he back three
and a half seven sort with tuck right at
the top of the degree of difficulty
three point three here's the DD which of
course will be multiplied by the marks
that she gets tenth after round two
when you ready
or she's having a big think about it
wasn't she
yeah people wondering well what he
taking so long for thinking it through
and potentially that could be paralysis
by analysis thinking too much trying too
hard
talk to self out of it there we go what
a shame kicking up towards the ceiling
which is way way too late the takeoff
was good every work was good staying on
the diving board I think a little bit
too long put herself off talk to herself
out of it now she's got some work to do
this young Mexican is there an ideal
length of time you take to do that
divert preference you know not too long
and if you rush too much you know you
need to give yourself time to be
composed but I think that for me was
potentially a little bit too long but
then of course if she nailed it I'd have
to eat my words mm-hmm thirty nine point
six zero though he's not a great return
on that dive early in length of time
that she considered it Rosalie and filly
on 18th now inward three and a half
summer swaps with tuck three point two
for the Canadian war she's struggling a
little bit today Alex de Partie in the
rest of the Canadian contingent there
cheering her on but she certainly needs
to lift a game that's a poor second man
dive and a poor third round dive
certainly for this young lady standards
she might get five and a half's and
sixes on this one but after a poor
second round dive it would need to be
better super-slow-motion yeah she's a
safe distance from the diving board but
not a very safe entry into the water
unfortunately yeah not quite sure what's
going on today a lot of missed dives or
times very much under par sixes they
give the judges and that's not going to
help her status a great deal she was
eighteenth of the previous round going
on others to falter here Melissa woo and
her back three and a half
we're tuck before and see how she
performs
those all going a little bit askew on
the take-off they're moving too far away
from the diving board not quite getting
your arms to on the take-off and having
a little bit of trouble to rotate here
we go look
yep needed to reach up a little bit more
before she came into a shape she was
always running out of room she does an
ok job of getting into the water there
but you can see her turning turning into
a little bit of a banana as she went in
needs to be straight and vertical as you
go in not with a big back arch that
would hurt she went in hopefully she's
okay shots now that was a banana
reference sixty two point seven zero for
Melissa whoo and at the moment with my
few holding it back to Chava the coach
going out myself as I went in she's in
2/3 back entry to think about as she
goes into round 4 here's Carillo of
Germany it were two and a half well
that's the best I've out of the three so
far from the rear for easiest dive two
point eight degree of difficulty so she
knows that she needed to make it count
and she certainly has Oh maybe touching
the toes on the diving board there these
girls it's often the case and even wood
two and a half in the pike position does
she do it will it stay with this shot oh
no she just all a toenail away with her
toenails she's glad she cut them this
morning
that could have been unfortunate seven
point five eight seven point five they
count towards the score of sixty four
point four zero remember all the marks
with lines through them do not count top
and bottom discarded the middle three
added up with the degree of difficulty
as you can see and that shot we are in
armstand territory again it's at 3.2
again and it's the back double
somersault one and a half twists around
like meat intake of breath
well she's overcooked it she cranked it
up on the start and gave it a bit too
much so diving is right being precise
she just gets after the dive a little
bit too aggressively doesn't have time
to you know to slow it down there's
nothing she could do there she was
always gonna over rotate on that needed
to flick up a little bit more with the
feet rather than flicking down
increasing the rotation nothing she
could do that mistake on the takeoff
over rotation on the end well we've
talked up a lot of the competition so
far I'd say I think this is a little bit
of a below par prelims to be honest so
we're waiting for somebody to really
bring it to life and to light up the
board becomes Kim of Korea back three
and a half somersaults with tuck three
point three degree of difficulty so that
she is a substantial distance away from
the board so the comparison beginning a
little bit too close for comfort well
she's done a really good job there I was
looking at Bob they're giving him the
sign for this could go either way
I've been watching this in training I'm
not sure whether she's gonna nail this
one or whether she could go crashing
into the water as I watch to do just
before this contest started anyway Kim
nailing her biggest dive when it counts
the back three and a half she placed a
waiting game pops her feet up directly
towards the ceiling
he should get herself some good somewhat
good marks on that one putting herself
in contention for a top eighteen spot at
the moment 70s are a very good score
you're getting 70s you are moving up the
pecking order you know starting to get
yourself in contention because they've
been so many forties and around about
that's got a few people are tailing off
here's a 2.9 from Annie Rivera
I mean that's gonna get out 20s yeah
just showing you how difficult diving is
now let's be fair we are at the Olympic
Games are watching the best of the best
and when you do it so well it almost
looks easy but let me tell you it's far
far from easy and this is example how
easy it can go wrong you've only got one
point six seconds to get your dive in in
this case not get it in 2.5 s can frayed
and the way things are panning out she
will not be returning for the semi-final
there's so many calamities today you
can't predict at this stage Tracy took
it of malaise yet a little bit more safe
with a two point nine back two and a
half summer sorts with pike 21st at the
moment I'm not returning as things stand
for all these well just a little bit
over watch the diver Anna before her we
go very very shorted vertical using the
same dive or opting for the same dive
Tracy decides to hang on longer than she
needs to
reaching over just tipping over a
vertical four and a half fives yep
she'll be way off the pace as well those
those rings as well they're good marker
for you see how far they are away from
the board for landing in the Rings and
she very nearly did basically took it
it's not gonna help her cause a great
deal forty seven point eight five now
I'm intrigued by the build-up to this
dive from Katie Bell just be quiet for a
second Bob
but you know chat to herself she
in with three and a half take it away
Casey
oh and it certainly worked this time 1 2
3 go is what you heard from a young miss
belt and then away she went and there's
Steve Foley national performance
director watching on from the audience
there and Bell this is the dive of her
meet look at that
wicked entry into the water super
slow-motion safe disses from the diving
board it's a big dive difficult to make
she disappears into the water good work
hurrah we've got a dive to save her last
and she has to after a couple of not
great rounds that's much much better
seventy eight point four zero and she's
given us ever chance up into 15th now I
am saying nothing about this diver apart
from what she's gonna do mister reversed
three and a half somersaults with tuck
three point three degree of difficulty
for the top-ranked Mexican
well she dies a lot better when you
don't say anything well that is she's
here only lady to choose to use this
dive it is incredibly difficult and well
the degree of difficulties three point
three and that's too low for this time
it used to be three point four and then
FINA messed around with the degrees of
difficulty and this dive suffered it's
much more difficult than the back three
and a half it is the reverse three and a
half normally seen only in the men's
competition parlor just showing her well
amazing dynamic diving style and that's
so best Ivan she needed it seventy two
point six zero she does it best when I
say nothing at all
now on to yulia coulton over of mexico's
rate of russia she's moved a bit for
three now some sort spike well it's
steady so you had a poor second round
dive didn't see this young lady so it
needed to be good quite a few girls with
a bit of work to do and this young lady
coming out on a third round with a
forward three and a half it's a good
pike shape all looks good to here just
maybe a touch short of vertical but
still if it gets over 70 points there
with the judges looking on with the
devices in the hands ready to input the
scores and they should be appearing on
your screen shortly for the russian
diver
now I go up of Japan let's go below it
was seventy three point five zero for
Colton over on to the back three and a
half for the Japanese with tuck or what
a big dive this is the hardest that
she's going to perform back three and a
half you seen lots of the girls
faltering on this one many of them
choosing the easier backward two and a
half in the pipe position
I think our really going out on this one
as to squeezing her hands are a bit high
in that touch choke close to the knees
she doesn't okay but she seems to bend
her knees as she goes in which kissing
pressure she was short but when she
wasn't so moving her feet too early look
she goes in just collapsing a little bit
on entry which is a shame yeah dozen
backup the 71 point four and the 72 for
Nakagawa 66 for the Japanese but okay
for her in terms of being back for the
semi quite safe territory in six at the
moment Kim of Korea finally in this
round you know I was watching this in
training and I was hoping it would it
would be better than training but that's
exactly what she's been doing in
training she's only 14 years old she's
in the Olympic Games and actually these
guys a little bit too difficult for her
she shouldn't really be doing these
times until she's more proficient at the
lower level look at that she's very
lucky not to really hurt yourselves
though that's only gonna get more twos
maybe she must have hurt us I'm sure but
she could have really hurt herself and
look she's she's fun to decide she's
okay yeah coach is saying you should
well I'm not sure what he's saying but
well app rider said he'd be hurt if her
body is not for those marks that come up
on the screen three two point five and
two will count towards her score twenty
four point seven five so the end of
round three women's 10-meter platform
Chinese one and two no real surprise
there the Australian three and four
likewise all those
that front page are feeling okay about
themselves as far as money cladding is
concerned she has a little bit of a
buffer there 19 points away from
problems but look at Paulo Espinoza
Sanchez bronze medal is from last year
in 18th place hanging on by a
fingernails
Stacy Powell has made up a bit of ground
she was 25th she's now 21st after round
three
around for about to start with the
woman's it's four rounds then five and
then with the men it's five rounds and
six so we also have an extra round for
the men before we get to the conclusion
of their program we'll see later on in
the week for the women it's five and the
degree of difficulty not quite as high
Stacy how are waiting for her turn and
for Great Britain and first up the best
position and we're gonna have a change
of judges after three rounds we change
the people with the devices to the video
came from Wiltshire house devices here
they are
favorite judges back hand a lot there's
just one less away from being a
Wimbledon champion
so just to remind you how the judges
work all seven judges input their scores
into the score pad and the device they
hold in their hands those seven schools
are calculated or actually put together
there are two high sand - Louis -
discounted they will be shown with the
lines through them the three that count
and multiplied by the degree of
difficulty which gives the total for
that particular dive first diver in
round four of the woman's 10 metre
platform preliminary is from the USA it
is Brittany violet and she will perform
at slightly lower tariff time and
slightly lower that 2.9 degree of
difficulty on this back two and a half
somersaults formed in the pike position
it's a good dive from Brittany opening
up three good ones already in the bag
and then this one just a little over she
goes into the water backwards spinning
so you can only see where you've been
not where you're going so as to judge
where to point your feet up just miss
timing it they're slightly reason over
she goes she'll get sixes she wanted
more than that yeah save it she goes in
no programs rather tailed off as near
was so good scores of 1773 now 57
followed by 53 she's starting to just
hurtle down the top 18 standings but she
was eight after round three so should be
okay finding the fianc award happens
later on
audrey LeBeau france for three and a
half summer sorts with pike just getting
into the realms of the threes now 3.0
exactly on her dive number four Wow some
faults starting to come in now it's very
difficult to hold your concentration on
such a long competition remember each
dive takes around 1.6 seconds and then
you go and sit down for 20 minutes or so
in between dives and then need to get
yourself back in the game and Audrey
their faltering over a vertical lots of
splash being thrown up
Wow they'll put it off the pace this
pack is really being shuffled right
before our eyes
that's why I said we were ready to write
anybody off at this stage because into a
good position and then immediately
undoes all the good work forty point
five zero or dueler boat it's not gonna
help sixteenth after round three
probably outside the top eighteen after
this now understand time for Megan Ben
feet OH three point three degree of
difficulty attached to this one it's an
arm stand back with tuck well everyone's
having to go maybe I'm not sure what's
happening out there you can tell like
the swim to the side she does not want
to come up and hear the scores or looks
okay so far and then just thinking she's
rotating slower than she is so pointing
your toes up a little bit too high
misjudging ending over a vertical mixed
bag to Seamus three point three and that
isn't going to count really the degree
of difficulty you need more raw scores
more execution marks for the judges 5.5
isn't going to cut it any obvious reason
why the standard tonight isn't really
not kind of good off base level has it
at any stage a bit unfair to some of the
divers who have had a little bit of
brilliance and as we move on to the
Olympic champion let's see if she can
buck the trend general in back three and
a half somersaults see how it should be
done from the Chinese well it was good
it was better than what we have been
seeing but it's not at the standard of
the Olympic champion that we would be
accustomed to it's a big dive those
three point three let's not take away on
how difficult it is and up until this
point is perfect just a little bit over
she goes into the water it's gonna get
over 70 points and in women's platform
diamond over 70 points is very good and
sometimes we see them get over 80 as
well well she did in the previous round
eighty one point six zero but this time
round and there
we're near as good ayuh tariff 270 4.25
no doubting that she will be in the top
18 come the end of this competition
equal fourth going into round 4 Julia
got Chuck again yes the arm stand three
points okay let me explain what she's
done there this is why we have the
official at the back of the diving board
to see if this happens so this is
actually a restart so she's gone to lift
up into the handstand she is over
balance and she's come down now what
will happen is she will perform the dive
that the judges will mark out of ten as
normal but then there will be a
two-point deduction from each judge for
the restart so I'll explain that when
the marks come up so she has to compose
herself forget that she's just made a
glaring error or what a shame all she
needed to do was lift her chin as she
went back into the water and that would
have been spot-on well nothing you could
do about the restarts of the judges as I
explained will mark kind of 10 there
will be a two-point deduction from each
of the judges and then it will be
multiplied by the degree of difficulty
to give the total so it's a shame the
dive wasn't a little bit better for she
did all the hard work and then she
needed to look back a little bit more
with her chin to get up light as she
went into the water let's have a look so
she would have gone 7 reads 5 7 and 1/2
reads five and a half and seven 1/2
reads five and a half to give the total
of 52
[Music]
there's no point the coach telling her
she knows exactly what she had to do
when she didn't do crowd really getting
behind Stacy Powell who's done a little
reparation job in round three still
little bit more what to do she can see
everybody else faltering she has a
chance to take advantage of that with a
3.2 inward three-and-a-half somersaults
with tuck very talented young diver when
she came through at Crystal Palace
we've done in leaps and bounds and I
can't she do it literally with this
fourth round I of Stacy pal
oh she needed to be better than that
very poor second mind I've just off a
game here real shame I was standing up
and clapping this dive in training which
was you know just ten minutes before the
start of this competition here
staying in the Tuck shape to long chin
in on the chest look at all that splash
being thrown up well there's been lots
of divers who are making mistakes and
Stacey is one of them one more dive to
go and that would need to be nailed in
order to for her to get through 48 I'm
afraid that's a sorry tale for Stacey
fives and the up to 48 so she's a 29 and
a 48 that could ultimately be the
difference between her getting through
to the semi-final and not bad key of
Italy inward three and a half in the
tuck position
well this is nemi's most difficult dive
and she has certainly turned it on when
it came to lots of her competitors
falter around her nose if she wants to
make it through this most difficult dive
of hers needed to be good and that will
get seven and a half's and eight maybe
and a big score judges just inputting
their scores into their machines and
this is what they say seven point five
and eight four near me back heat and
seventy five point two and she's been
most consistent divers here tonight
hasn't been below 65 in any of the
rounds Ian Stewart of Germany 12th after
round three it's back two and half
someone's again but degree of difficulty
down below the threes into two point
nine it's normally one of our better
dives and it proves the same today very
consistent on this backwards spinning
move seems to know exactly where she is
spotting the water twice as she spins
around showing the strain on the takeoff
there they still get eight and a half
for sure it's a beautiful dive reaches
back in looking for that rip entry and
there it is underlining why sometimes
the lower tariff dives have a safety
first option and she just proved it with
a two point nine when the three point
three haven't been working for others
she pigs have a nice decent solid score
and she can jock her weight into the top
18 fairly soon with times like that
seventy-three point nine five mana
cladding being a good reaction a good
support a good reception from the home
crowd she performs we've come on Monique
from Mercer me in the crowd she's trying
to compose herself they get an idea just
what she has to do know she has to go
fantastic shot that's it back two and a
half sour sorts with Mike two point nine
Monique it's been the breathing right
getting the posture right 14th after
round three
well she's let it go as well he's a real
shame the take off look good she has
been struggling with the neck injury
maybe that was she was protecting it a
little bit she didn't look back and she
came out seemed to stay in a slight dish
position letting the dive go over all
just overcooked it over she goes and
that's a poor dive for Monique as well
has she done enough one more dive to go
and all to play for to make this top 18
Cup
well first three round eyes were okay so
she's got a little bit of margin of
error thirty nine point one five will
pull her back a little bit and she was
14th out around three so it's tight for
qualification you need an of China third
after round three
well everyone's having a go at making
mistakes this evening just showing you
how difficult it is to perform
consistently in this level of
competition
lots of divers and lots of waiting in
between dives and some lapses in
concentration even fom who you Dan
well sure she goes in throwing up the
splash maybe I know four and a half five
and you're gonna get about 50 points
I'm really really puzzled by this
Espinoza having an off night new you Dan
having really an off night wants to grab
this competition I know that the marks
won't be carried forward but you've got
to get in that top 18 she should have a
bit of a safety buffer anyway but it's
amazing the best divers in the world not
coming to terms with this competition so
far a few notable exceptions came on
yang with her back three and a half
somersaults with tuck big degree of
difficulty for her 3.3 right and she
will go leaping up the standings and
into the top 18
your get it.white she does well there we
go
bucking the trend once again one or two
divers refusing to fall in rapport with
all the others who seem to be faltering
left right and center Kim here
absolutely nailing her back three and a
half that's really good that should get
close to 80 points and that's going to
be one of the highest going dives of the
competition so far well I can be done
and she has just done it seventy nine
point two zero is on my screen with
confirmation on yours there it is
eight times the degree of difficulty and
240 point nine zero and she's within
touching distance of returning tomorrow
morning there's any broken back three
and a half for her three point three in
the tough position
oh it's a most difficult dive and a lot
of girls faltering on this one Brittany
they're the young 16 year old holding it
together it's not the best she's ever
done it I've watched her in training but
she's got such power look at that double
almost by board-level
knows where she is just moving her feet
a little bit too high but yeah that's
going to get high 60s which is good
enough especially in this level of
contests you can afford not to dive at
your best and still make it through
effortlessly you know I think the judges
are actually quite happy to see a dive
they can give some marks if so maybe
they get a little bit more than they
deserve but seventeen point nine five is
okay that's very good I understand as of
tonight and she will go into second
place for the time being and up there
with the best brenda spazzy ani of italy
arm stand back double somersault one
half twist three point two degree of
difficulty move all you've seen now this
can go wrong the effort you have to be
put through and go through it's going to
be precise
well Brenda seemed okay all the way
through that dive and then just couldn't
seem to hold the splash down as she went
in the dives a little bit maybe
aggressive on the start a little bit too
much rotation means the over rotation
and the entry here you go can't quite
stop it and then the splash rolls over
another mediocre dive very ordinary dies
here this evening for a lot of the women
what do the judges rate or reckon to
that really very highly at all 5.5 and a
5-4 right at the end but I won't count
and that's a mark and Sebastiani won't
be overly encouraged by 51 point 2 0 for
the Italian now on to Karolina Hernandez
of Mexico joint 19th the last round in a
long preparation for she lifts off with
an inward three and a half somersaults
with tuck and three point two is the
degree of difficulty on this one she's
having to dig deep to get herself back
in contention and that was certainly
help 3.2 degree of difficulty real shame
on her previous dive she made a real
mess of it this one fortunately she's
back in the kind of form she's been
showing in training only 15 years old
Mexico riding high from recent successes
and then and as here trying to get back
in contention and I think that might
help that's not gonna hinder her after
some of them are too seen yeah I think
in the 7.5 range is pretty good by
tonight standard 72 for here that's why
the smile is back on the face she
contemplates hopefully being back in the
top 18 for the semi-final filly on
I'm stand back triple somersault way too
close to the exclusion zone at the
moment
three point three degree of difficulty
slightly more difficult to understand
than the previous one or she's nailed it
and she needed to again faltering on the
second and third round dives here so
fourth way and dive the highest equal
highest degree of difficulty three point
three so tricky balancing hands she's
quite high on a tux check he does manage
to dig your fingernails into the top of
her knees there and hang on in there for
the ride and she makes it
mid-seventies and that'll certainly move
up the field yeah she'll be much happier
with that after a couple of days I
haven't quite got her way that one
definitely does and the mark of seventy
five point nine zero and up the
standings and she can start to think one
more dive hopefully I will be safe for
tomorrow but nobody in the ten downward
stage can really be thinking that right
now
Melissa whoo in with three and a half
somersaults for the Australian well over
she goes hard work done
aerial work is good and then just the
exit from the dive she isn't predicting
it correctly either see in the water at
the right time is a real shame because
it all looks good so far and then she
just miss times at entry and over she
goes splash throws back towards the
diving board and even Melissa whoo
having a wobble out there fifty-four
point four zero and the top marks are
eluding many of the top divers
that's how it stands at the moment chin
roben and backe we're still quite a few
names to go next up will be Maria Cuyo
Germany from Berlin and it's a back two
and a half somersaults one and a half
twist for her yeah it's okay
she yeah her seemed to get it all
working in the right way in the end some
interesting movements before she took
off but got there in the end here we are
one and a half twist a little bit low on
the water here but she plays the waiting
game looks at the water punches a hole
with her hands and gets in relatively
clean not so much splash pretty average
mediocre ordinary six is 6.5 s don't
really know I've got a word that I can
use for that but there we go it's hard
to know what is mediocre today those
noon sixty two point four zero for the
gem and that might just be good enough
to slider up the standings and get her
on the cusp of making the stop a team to
the Malaysian and a tank top position
for the inward three-and-a-half tenth
after around she's on fire today one of
the few that are actually performing
look it up punch in the air from the
Malaysian coach he likes it and I
certainly do
thank you it's nice to see some well
executed dives and this from panda Lella
superb will it get over 80 points and
wake up the competition a little bit and
keep me keep me on the edge of my seat
it needs it in these shaky that grabbing
the hands punching a hole in the water
taking all this all the air down with
her causing a suction suction excuse me
for that entry I think it's about the
fourth eighty of the night so I would
for 4/5 I've been to many more than that
eighty one point six zero four and Anna
yeah we've been sleeping too
here's Kim Jin och I'm Stan for her
you're kissing the board yeah using an
incredible amount of arm strength
they're very gymnastic on her wanna
approach and the technical take off here
we go look at this looks like a vault oh
she did she actually put her nose on the
platform Wow
that can't be very comfortable I would
like to bang my nose on the platform
before then flick off with the legs who
actually pops up one twisting in very
peculiar and uncomfortable I would
suggest but there we go the divers
alright no bruise on the nose that I can
see and 65 points to take away with her
well obviously any occasion would
improve it but sixty five point one zero
for Kim and she's up to 12 now Annie
Rivera of Cuba her turn to do the three
point two version there's a three point
three version 3.2 version of the arm
stand back a double somersault one and a
half twists that's one of her better
dives today have really struggling out
there today the young Cuban and it's
nice to see her landed the water without
hurting herself the previous dive would
of course just some discomfort that one
on her head that yeah she'll be one of
the few I think there's the eight that
won't be going through into the top 18
and she'll be one of them fives and one
six
a total mark 50 4.40 Tracy took yet of
Malaysia and it looks like she's on her
way through hopefully at the moment
Tracy is not 2.7 were right down the
bottom of the scale here reverse two and
a half it's well executed and his bobble
suggesting she is off the pace at the
moment only 24th after the previous
round probably needed to be a little bit
better on this although it is one of her
bed of efforts reverse two and a half
standing for was jumping away from the
diving board spinning backwards towards
it'll get sevens 7.5 maybe there's low
DD so probably won't get too too close
to at well close to 60 pretty much on
the button there Leon 60 point seven
five for Tracy
7.5 and that's better they're not quite
good enough just the swimsuit talk to
yourself have a chat
Thank You Stefan
back three and a half somersaults for
Katie Bell that's 24 year old Walker
County we're gonna get this time
oh it's a good dive two five six seven
eight counting certainly work for this
time it seems to be very fidgety but on
a nervous-looking character on the end
of the diving board but if any of you
sitting at home we're up on the 10 meter
I'm sure your heart would be beating a
little bit quicker than normal normally
and Katie Bell they're nailing a fourth
round dive backing up in the third round
dive of home at three and a half with a
back three and a half this is the
highest degree of difficulty and she's
made it came Michele Shooto up the
leaderboards yeah five six seven eight
taking steps to put things right
seventy nine point two zero on to the
bronze medalist from last year at the
World Championships we haven't seen that
kind of form so far and she is flirting
with going out 18th place I'll go see
the real howler Espinoza Sanchez on this
dive in with three and a half
somersaults three point two
well that's much more like it that is a
nod towards the real polar Espinoza
Sanchez silver medalist their partner
witness synchronized platform diving a
lot better in the synchronized platform
of course this is more like it little
over at vertical but that will get eight
mid-70s again to go with the 72 from the
third round I think she's back
approaching the top end of the field or
certainly they're the top ten well it's
a nifty they're up a few places for the
time being up to 13th from 18th and that
will be secure of course you can start
all over again in the semis
if she does make it Julia
Carlton over 9th at the moment two more
dives for her to come and it's the
inward three-and-a-half somersaults tuck
position 3.2 is the degree of difficulty
she's just over the 200 mark it's a
little low on the water but managed to
get out and make just in time to get the
impression that she was vertical as she
went in the judges will take marks off
her being a low finish diving board yeah
it's a little bit over with an arch as
well I don't know I don't know what I
get that actually a little bit close a
little bit low six and a half maybe I
don't know I didn't really like it that
much
oh just being about generous perhaps 7.5
s will count as well the 7 on your
screen lines through the scores mean
they do not count multiplied by the
degree of difficulty 70 point 4 0 is how
you arrived at that mark my Nakagawa of
Japan 2.9 but she's already done some
good work to get herself in sixth place
with two more dives for her to go
or over a vertical thrown up a load of
splash up until that point my Nakagawa
had been very very steady and very solid
whilst those around her were faltering
she seemed to be unwavering but this one
a little bit wavy and there's a wave as
she goes in throwing up a load of splash
that's a great shot isn't it super
slow-mo London 2012
Maia Maia give us a wave not with those
scores five point five and forty seven
point eight five again I said that not
what she would have wanted like passing
the baton right I'm not doing very well
your turn now Kim suji it's around
things off reverse two and a half seven
sorts oh that's so best I've why I was
maybe you heard it I took a sharp intake
of breath as she took off I wasn't sure
which way up she was gonna land but
whether her feet were gonna come close
to the diving board which they do a
little bit she hangs on in there
squeezing in and then yep she blocks it
on her head safely and securely for her
best diver this contest
sadly she has so much ground to make up
she has she hasn't made up any ground at
all in terms of position because she was
26th
she is 26th
but good much better brought the smile
back to her face and all most of the
coaches we're not quite end-of-round for
a shake-up in that round wasn't there
Chen from roben hang up to third you
know Chinese Hugh is down to sink so 264
in 9th place who's an 18 and and is an
none of the Brits in the top 18 at the
moment how much do they have to do to
make up the ground are they cast adrift
or can they repair the damage take a lot
mone cladding in 20th place and Stacy
Powell in 22nd anybody pretty much below
that is out of the competition
well our standard of the men's three
mates in last night was exemplary and
hurts on the edge of our seats we're
kind of waiting for this competition to
come to life hasn't done yet but there's
so much still to be done and so many
twists and turns in the last round and
still more places to be gained a lot of
places to be lost top 18 remember ok
12th as Brittany viola is she is safe
but she got a feel for program and
underlying that fact we have a range of
dives from her to finish off the program
it's a back two and a half somersaults
one and a half twist with pike three
point two can she finish off in style
well yes she can very very good entry
into the water however I think she's
over twisted let's look at the replay
the judges kept well if they spot it
they should penalize for that the divers
should be square side on as you go in
there we are rocking and rolling a
little bit and I can see both ankles and
both Castor's she went in that means
that she's over twisted so the judges
could look at that rocking and rolling
not in a good way though like driving an
out-of-control bus but she managed to
square it up that's good
22 touch another chubby Checker's there
but she gets away with it
sevens for Brittany viola and she will
be returning in the semi-finals not a
statement I can make at the moment I'm
out Audrey LeBeau she could back two and
a half sour thoughts 1/2 twist 21st 3.2
degree of difficulty for the French
woman's a final dive oh I don't think
she'll be coming back with that
definitely not in fact if she was in
21st place which is what the scores
scoreboard says than that Wow
blown dive to finish bit of a shambles
oh what a shame short low scores
disappointing end come on I thought we
were gonna get a finish with a flourish
it's not happening firm miss Leveaux
Baga votes for mr. Taylor while we're at
it very 6.80 for Audrey LeBeau now Megan
in Fito next 14th a lot of Canadian
support both in the crown Dino watching
on TV as well she performs her back
two and a half somersaults one and a
half twist Pike position 3.2 yes to
confirm her semi-final place finally
someone who wants to get in the final
somebody wants to make it through who's
almost unscathed from this prelim not a
great day for Megan some good stuff and
then some very mediocre stuff on this
already Olympic bronze medalist from
last week the solid finish though
that'll get over 70 points and through
she goes yep puts the top of the pile
for the time being its qualification
well and truly achieved coach happy she
should be too and all the things she got
wrong tonight she can rectify again in
the morning general in olympic and world
champion in position number ones you
might expect for somebody with those
accolades back two and a half
somersaults one hard twists to finish
yep no mistakes all night from cherylin
although she hasn't been top of a game
if she doesn't really need to she is
head and shoulders and miles I in front
of everyone else and she should be a
clear Victor by well over 50 points one
and a half twist two and a half
somersaults vertical entry and hardly
any splash you can see why she's olympic
and world champion it bitch have been
only 15 she's now grand old age of 19
and she'll be tough to beat
she is currently not only number one but
67 points ahead of Megan Ben feet oh
that's how much better she has been
diving and the top Canadian at the
moment Julia we got Chuck night after
round 4 time to line her transition into
the last 18 back to and half somersaults
one and a half twist you've seen it
before
and it comes again she's she's done some
fantastic dives and that one isn't one
of them unfortunately Wow hard work had
been done just making a bit of a
misjudgment on the finish one and a half
twist into the two and a half
somersaults stretches forward too far
ends up short and under twisted so
she'll get sixes and 6.5 to do it of a
disappointing finish for this young girl
here I can see both anchors again the
judges may even people while they've
gone with her it's okay yeah total mark
60 point eight zero and 324 will be
enough to see her through now Stacy
Powell proud doing everything they can
to lift her first of the British
competitors but this has to be her best
dive of the night by some way and
whereas this will be the end of Stacie's
competition for places outside
qualification and the marks are there
for her if she can get this right back
two and a half somersaults and one and a
half twists used to be a high degree of
difficulty very high three point two
for Britain's Stacy Powell well that's
more like it she really really needed to
pull it out the bag and she has now will
it be enough I'm not sure it's a really
really good dive it's gonna get eights
it may even get 8.5 s is the entry clean
enough to get eights from the judges
it's 3.2 I've seen it much better than
this just throwing up a little bit too
much splash maybe the judges won't go
with it finally she does a dive that
she's capable of but I think she might
have left it too late too much to do
yeah I'm not sure the mark that's coming
up here is gonna be good enough 70 point
4 0 she didn't get the eights you needed
on the 8.5 7.5 will accrue and Stacy I'm
afraid it looks like you will not be
returning in the semi finals but there's
still some room
other things to go wrong Naomi back e
2.7 lowest degree of difficulty we've
seen Reverse two and a half Oh
faltering on a final dive her lowest
degree of difficulty she was way up
there in the top end of the field
right in the business end of the field
and now she has well saved her worse for
last unfortunately here we go the
takeoff is good this is her best dive
normally when she kicks out way too late
way over look at that tidal wave
surfboard momen have a drink on us boys
44.5 5 for bat key
well she may already have done enough
anyway I'd have to be too concerned
about that last round dive to a fish
with a flourish and she hasn't Christine
Stewart after a great start twist right
and she will go for a for three and a
half several sorts with pike your superb
a rip head tree into the water the
vertical splash las' that's gonna get
some good marks from the judges even
though her takeoff is a little bit weak
she's not the most powerful of the women
here finishing a little bit low on the
water but that or get eights I'm sure
because of that superb entry that's the
best dive we've seen for christen this
evening what's your secure place in the
semi-final effortlessly with that one
yeah she had a very poor start 51.80 but
then 72 72 73 and 72 and yes smile can
remain there for a bit longer
because she will be returning now
Monique 20th position after around 4 she
has a few points to make up because the
equation is if she does it's like she
has done it I can do it
that's for three and a half somersault
could be her passage into the last 18
3.0 degree of difficulty looking
70 80 marks really put her there
oh yeah it's straight up and down
this occurred entry into the water so
will it be good enough will it be good
enough to cried of expecting the crowd
are wanting so she was in xx after the
previous rhinos only 3.0 degree of
difficulty that's a good time to finish
on she's clean into the water she
probably needs more than 7 and 7.5 s I
think that's what she's going to get
with that effort and she will have an
agonizing wait now looking at the
scoreboard to see whether her total
score we shall be on your screen shortly
is good enough to secure a spot in the
top 18 well she's gone over 300 which is
encouraging sixty seven point five zero
is quite encouraging its margins its
fractions and it could be very very
tight still she's giving herself a
chance who you Dan of China back two and
a half seven sorts one and a half twists
to finish with Pike position for the
second ranked Chinese and she's been
very mediocre today now that the you Dan
is normally something quite special I
would expect it to see her up pushing a
teammate Shin rule in but she's been way
off the pace today only in sixth after
the fourth round of dives I don't think
that's gonna move up the rankings at all
short she goes in thrown at the splash
and there's not much of her to throw up
splash so yeah she's off her game this
evening but she'll be back tomorrow in
the semi final well on our screen only
to have definitely qualified so far and
that is Chen of China and Christian step
we have a big queue beside us on the
scoreboard and it tells us who has made
it through as they make it through and
to have especially how tight this
competition is come on yang of Korea
People's Republic of Korea in 19th place
if this goes right she will have at
least five more dives in this
competition
oh I'm sure the whole of the British
team were holding their breath because
she was in 19th and of course Monique
cladding was in 20th her teammates
they're really getting behind her and
that was a very good dive to finish and
showing ladies been on for a couple of
dives and off for a couple and she's
finished on a good one there that's
gonna be very close I think that we'll
put it above Monique cladding and so Wow
well monix fine I'll be enough for her
to get through this young lady Kim
Mike's final die was sixty seven point
five zero and Kim's final dive was sixty
seven point two zero it was a big enough
margin between the two of them that's
not gonna close up sufficiently for
Monique at this stage when there are
others still to come
could falter along the way Brittany
roben looked pretty impeccable so far
mr. finish back two and a half seven
sorts one and a half twists for the
young Australian well she's just a
little bit short she went in that she's
been really really impressive not
finishing on her best I've oak well
certainly she didn't perform that dive
at her best I was watching this in
training and it was certainly better
than this finishing a little bit low on
the water means that she's short she
goes in that's a poor effort by her
standards to finish off the competition
but she was way up there in the top
three almost after four finds well it
might be her lowest mark of the evening
it is fifty seven point six zero but she
has qualified as has who of China so
both the Chinese through only four have
yet
don't be queue beside their name to
indicate that they are through so still
plenty of positions up for grabs
speciali the 2.8 is not gonna get there
back one and a half somersaults to an
art West 24th place have to be the best
like one and a half she's ever done but
even though it probably wouldn't make it
no it's a nice time to finish but no
semi-final place for Brenda
Pazhani from Italy she's been okay this
evening but a few errors early on when
that she's left herself too much to do
low tariff dive to finish 2.8 and she
won't be featuring in tomorrow morning's
semi-final so their job at the Royal
Albert Hall probably up for grabs
she can go and conduct the orchestra
after that way for Brenda
next up is Karolina Hernandez of Mexico
and she is right on the last
qualification position no pressure them
18th place back two and a half
somersaults one and a half twists she
and Manik take a long time over their
preparation thinking about making a cup
of tea now might be a good time
all there you go so she was an 18th
after the 4th rounds and that is not
gonna help her campaign she will move
down the ranks with that that does help
some of the other women certainly money
cladding who is watching now the
scoreboard and hoping that she can make
it through there's nothing money can do
now but this young lady has just taken
herself out of contention
it's not work for her that's twice now
she's a laborious Lea long build-up to
that dive and it's not work firm when
she went quicker more quickly she'd much
better I don't quite that's the way she
does it didn't really work for her
tonight four point five and she moves
below
Monica cladding in the standings so
Malik has made up one place a couple
Chuck has qualified as we move on to
Rosalie and filly on 17th for Canada no
room for error no margin for mistakes no
mistakes
that will keep her in the top 18 which
of course is where she wants to be
hasn't had the best day on the diving
boards here today we can expect to see
so much more from this lady
of course she's an Olympic medalist
already last week in the synchro
competition with the fellow Canadian
who's also featured here today making
benefit oh so hurry up Rosaline in on a
head and safety through to the
semi-finals good work from the Canadian
girls care something other divers would
buy that 7 7 and 7.5 off her just to
give themselves a bit of insurance a bit
of a buffer she's done what she had to
do and yeah yes from the coach and
she'll be returning
well just over 12 hours from now well
it's a whoo
to finish a back two and a half
somersaults one and a half twists eighth
place on her way
yep Melissa safely on her way all the
way through into the semi-finals she's
been pretty steady this evening that's
what you needed to do to get through
unscathed we'll certainly see Melissa in
tomorrow morning's semi final hope you
can join us then
well I think the standard will have
improved sufficiently and quite markedly
from what we're seeing tonight even
though it will be early morning dives
for the divers which I don't
particularly like you might see a few
more of them on their game in the semi
there the marks for Melissa wood in
Australian contingent are vocal and
numerous and 72 is what she gets now
Maria curry up of Germany 10th place
she's probably over performed if
anything tonight 2.9 nice steady secrets
of dies from hurt back two and a half
somersaults yep very steady and she just
bunks that one on her head just as she
needs to to make it through safely yeah
very steady solid last round dive 2.9
and the backward two-and-a-half in the
pike position she knows where she is
points to toes back up towards the five
round the five meter height and then
drifts back glides back fake it
certainly good enough for a semi-final
place underlining her 10th position from
the previous round still 10th with about
sixty two point three five when he
competed in the synchro now in the
individual she's picking up more where
she left off them from the synchro she's
gonna act together tonight and hang
back two and a half of hurt you had the
back turn half with one and a half twist
lots of the girls finishing on this one
almost landed on the camera down there
as she went so deep into the water
some of you can see this were some of
you asking about the sprays and sprays
of course disturb the surface of the
water so as planned until comes around
here she can see exactly where the
surface of the water is to grab her
hands and punch the entry into the water
she said a great job out there today and
she'll certainly be one of the top
qualifiers as we go through to the
semi-finals
swinging for her marks to come up before
I can confirm her progression yeah in
Fito brag up Chuck that key and she goes
in as the second-highest qualifier so
far by hm so so far we have ten people
who have confirmed their place Kim
Jim okay and she 16th after Ralph or oh
that's very good that is good enough to
secure a place or teammates were on
their feet and so they should be she's
been working hard out there today very
good quality dives and this is one of
them but gets 70 points on this and if
it does she will make it through to the
semi-final job done wait for the judges
to input their marks it's about to
appear on your screen and here they come
7.5 s and a seven seventy point four
zero yeah the big Q is beside her name
she's the 11th qualifier for the
semi-final not likely to include and yet
Rivera
of Cuba but she's got a program to
finish off and yes that died again
and that's a bed of effort from for
money up she's had a tough day out there
today some of her dives well Oliver dies
actually going to miss this one is her
best dive of the competition lots of the
girls finishing on this one back two and
a half somersaults with one and a half
twist I'm taping on the shins there may
be suffering some shin splints quite
common in divers because they're
constantly doing exercises order to make
their jumps more explosive as if they
were heard low or a sprint up causing
great strain there we go Olympic prelim
complete 57.6 ceremony cladding waiting
nothing she can do now she's had her
five dives
she's reliant on everybody else not
getting over that 18 threshold diver
ranked 23 after round four Tracy took it
on Malaysia and it's that dive again a
lot of the divers in the final round
opting for the back two and a half more
very good time there for Tracy she yeah
as struggled a little bit out there but
she's finished very very strongly
they're like two and a half somersaults
one and a half twist you're getting used
to this one now three point two degree
of difficulty maps into the one and a
half twist and there she is into the
water vertically with hardly any splash
that's a great dive to finish but just
left herself too much to do to make it
through to the semi-finals up to 18th
for the time being but there are many
more divers to go Tanaka still further
down so she will not be returning bras
meaningfully on has confirmed her return
in the semis
seven point five and seven as the
Malaysian finishes off campaign okay
this young lady will win a few hearts
just by her preparation alone tonight
it's been entertaining the diving has
been its bit erratic but she's got it
together towards the end 13th place she
can't see the face on this one now we
can back two and a half somersaults one
half twist like we're having a
conversation here Katie
well whatever she's doing certainly
working for it the past three dives that
she's performed have been very good
indeed he's 78 point 78 points and this
one I think will be in the 70s once
again lots of divers opting you just a
little bit over vertical as she goes in
but that's gonna scooter continuing up
the leaderboard she will certainly be in
the top ten yeah we look forward to the
continuation of the Katie Bell chat show
tomorrow and she's through with that 72
she's probably bit of a chatterbox don't
you know Espinoza Sanchez I think for me
that's biggest disappointment of the
night but she will be back for more
provided everything goes to plan on this
back two and a half with pike no it's a
back two and a half somersaults with one
and a half twist three point two degree
of difficulty this is an important I for
her to finish on and she needed to
finish very well which she does we
expected to see more from this young
lady and I'm sure we will tomorrow she's
made it through relatively comfortably
in the end I'm pretty sure that will put
him in the top 12
after a very shaky first two round dive
she's back in the mix with that final
dive I'd give you an idea 39.6 in round
two but back to normality to expect from
the bronze medalist from last year oh I
can't have had down for a medal in this
competition but she hasn't really backed
up my statement with performance tonight
but that's okay Manik to the fans at
home desperately hoping you there she's
17 for the moment and also Nova's gonna
go above up round
yep there's a bit splashy she goes in
but that would be good enough to take
her through through the semi-final mr.
haire bounder she went in there hair
tied out the way to get right in your
face if you were doing multiple twisting
multiple somersaulting dives which she
is safely through marks please judges
here they come 64 for Colton over I
think she wanted a bit more than that my
look on her Facebook doesn't matter
because she can get more tomorrow when
she returns for the semi-final ill but
if this goes well for like a Gow up
there will be no British representation
in the semi-final it's back to and half
again cladding on the edge of her seat
well it's good to back two and a half
somersaults one and a half twist in the
pike position lots of girls using this
13.2 and that's Nakagawa through to the
semi-final with a solid last round dive
let's have a look what that does to the
standings and where it moves people to
look at that overhead shot just showing
you what they're the girls are
attempting to do impressive
well that 70 point four zero means the
home fan to have nobody's to support
they have to adopt somebody in the
semi-final because both Monique landing
and Stacy foul outside the top 18 as we
welcome for the final time the last
diver in Korea and she'll go for same
dive to finish well the youngest
competitor finishes up the polymerase
only 14 years old and I'm sure well she
must have enjoyed every second what an
absolute privilege to come and compete
at the Olympic Games when you're only 14
years old just over a vertical as she
goes in there she's gonna finish bottom
of the pile and she's been there all
competition
I hope she's enjoyed her Olympic
experience and coaches applauding her
efforts and that's a competition
complete she will finish at the bottom
of the standings tomorrow face though
she seems to have enjoyed the experience
and Allah you will be returning and 2nd
place 2nd place qualifier for the
Malaysian still chatting away hey RC
you're right old chatterbox aren't you
it's funny really this one of the
smallest divers in the contest has the
tallest coach with her it gives you such
a contrast isn't it so here we go the
standings after round 5 the final round
in the women's team meets a platform and
most of the big names are through pretty
much all the big names are through China
at the top China in 6th now this is the
agonizing wait for those who don't
already know I think pretty much all the
calculations have been done and the last
place claimed by Kim of People's
Republic of Korea who is the unfortunate
person just to miss out on the top 18
places it is money cladding Stacy Powell
in 20th so the two British competitors
just missing out in the a bit the
reserves for the semi-final and the boat
and Brenda spazzy on emo thought they'd
be in the top 18 it wasn't to be their
night tonight or indeed Aniyah Rivera
consolation for Mo'Nique consolation -
for Stacy and that young lady from the
USA big smile big headphones will be
ready to come back for the semi-final
which is 10 o'clock British summer time
wherever you're watching around the
world
check your clocks and your watches and
make sure you with us if it's pretty
easy to tell you it's gonna be in 12 and
a half hours or so from now
the semi-final of the woman's 10 metre
platform and I could tell you Chen was
in the end 43 points above pang of
Malaysia thank you for joining us
transmission here from the Aquatic
Centre at the heart of London's Olympic
Park
sadly no British competitors back
the semi-final but 18 will return as
well we look forward to seeing you then
bye
[Music]